美国二十世纪福克斯公司出品
字幕:将军的荣耀auv
翻译:将军的荣耀auv 上海电影译制厂
蓝天工作室
《What Is Love》
What is love If it's not with you
如果没有你那还叫什么爱
I know when you're alone you feel it too
你孤单的时候我知道你也能感觉到
In your arms is where I long to be
我渴望躺在你的臂弯
Cause being with you gives me sanity
因为和你在一起
oh...Listen to me darling
听我说亲爱的
I wake up every morning Thinking bout the way you feel
我每天早上醒来 想着你的感受
I wonder if you know it
不知你是否意识到
And what good is the party  If you're not around
如果你不在派对还有什么好
Listen to me now
现在听我说
What good is love
爱有什么好
If it's not your love
如果不是你的爱
What good is love
爱有什么好
If it's not your love
如果不是你的爱
It's a crazy party Im happy to be with everybody
这是疯狂的派对 我真高兴和大家一起狂欢
Balance Shake your body down to zhe ground Blu
宝贝儿把身体动起来 扭起来
该你 该你 该你了，布鲁
Me?
我
What's a song If you can't heart it too
如果你听不到 那还算什么歌
Can't imagine dancing without you
没有你我不可能跳舞
A shooting star, ain't really nothing to see
流星划过我视而不见
If you can not right standing next to me
如果没有你站在我身边
oh....Listen to me darling
听我说亲爱的
I wake up every morning Thinking bout the way you feel
我每天早上醒来 想着你的感受
I wonder if you know it And what good is the party
不知你是否知道 如果你不在
If you're not around Listen to me now
派对还有什么好 现在听我说
What good is love
爱有什么好
If it's not your love
如果不是你的爱
For a bird from Minnesota you've got some moves.
明尼苏达州来的鸟还有自己的舞步
Oh,actually that's wasn't a move,that was an acident.
这不是舞步，这是事故
But I accpt the compliment.
不过我接受你的恭维
It's great Rafael could watch the kids.
多亏拉斐尔能帮我们照顾孩子
Yeah,Looks like you're stuck with me all night.
是啊，这样今天你得和我在一起..一整晚
You are my one and only, Blu.
你是我的唯一 布鲁
Ah,that's a god thing, since I am the only other one.
那太好了，因为公的就剩我一个了
- Hi, lovebirds, happy new year!- Rafii, where are...
-比翼鸟 新年快乐 -拉斐尔 他们在哪？
Kids are with Luiz.no worries!
孩子们和路易兹在一起 不用担心！
Worries,right here.
担心？我们很担心
- Luiz, where are the kids?
- What? I don't have any kids.
-路易兹 孩子们呢？
-什么？我又没有孩子
Our kids!
我们的孩子
- oh,right,I felt them with Tiny. - Tiny?
-哦 对了 我交给小不点了
-小不点！
Why? She is an excllent babysitter.
干嘛 她可是这里最棒的保姆
I'm a terrible babysitter.
我是这里最差劲的保姆
This would be awesome!
这一定会很炫的
All right,I've done all the calculations,
and each explosion will be pperfectly synced to the beat.
行了 我已经计算过了 每次爆炸都会完美的踩在节奏点上
Unless I didn't carry the one.
除非我没有算上这个...
Here's my vision...Red, blue, green, yellow, yellow... purple.
我们这里会有红色 蓝色 绿色 黄色...紫色
And It'my vision...
我觉得会是...
I don't think your parents would like this very much
我觉得你们爸妈不会想看到这个的
Here we go.
那我们开始吧
- Where are you gonig little bird? - What is this?
-你这是要去哪儿啊小鸟
-这是什么？
- Dad! -Guys,you Know the rules,
-爸爸
-你们知道规矩的
No pyrotechnics without adult supervision.
没有大人的监督 不能放烟花
We asked Tiny.
我们问过小不点了
That's even worse. Sorry Tiny.
这就更糟了 抱歉小不点
You don't have to pay me, Mr Blu.
工钱我不要了 布鲁先生
Kids,Next time, ask me.
孩子们下一次要先问我
- But you always say no.  -No  I don't.
-可你每次都说不
-不 我没有
-dad,you're in denial.  -OK,honey,do I always say no?
-爸爸 你在否认现实   -好吧 亲爱的 我经常说不吗
Yes . I mean, no.
是的 哦 我是说...不...
Great, now Mom's saying it too.
太好了，现在妈妈也在说不了
Listen, we are the last Blue Spix's Macaws left on the planet,We have to stay safe.
听着 我们是地球上最后的蓝皮克斯金刚鹦鹉 我们得注意安全
-birds of blue feathers...  - have to stick together.
-有蓝色羽毛的鸟   -要团结在一起
I smell chicken.
我闻到烤鸡味了
No, no, no!
啊 不不不....
By my calculations that's like his twenty-seventh "no" today.
根据我的计算 这是他今天说的第27个不了
Help!
-救命   -啊...
Everybody,fly!  Happy New Year
大家伙 快跑
Oh man!How could only Dad got all the fun?
这不公平 凭什么 只有爸爸玩的这么爽
Look! It works!
看啊 成功了
Well,this year's off to a great start.
看来今年开了个好头
RIO 2
里约大冒险 2
Amazon Expedition. Day 7.
亚马逊之行 第七天
Two thousand miles from Rio
距里约热内卢 2000英里
We've reached  the center of the rainforest.
我们到达热带雨林的中心
As we effortlessly guide down the river.
当我们沿着河流毫不费力的向前划行的时候
We are surrounded by plants and animals struggling for survival.
周围都是挣扎生存的植物和动物
Effortless for you.
毫不费力的是你
How pretty!
哇哦 好漂亮
Oooh!Spit it out! Spit it out!
吐出来 快吐出来
We are near the nests of Amazoian wood quail.
Odontophorus gujanensis
我们已经接近亚马逊林鹑的栖息地
奥坦塔图莫 戈乔尼色斯
6 months ago, we rescued this little bird from smugglers.
六个月前我们从走私者手中救下这只小鸟
She was sick, malnourished, with a broken leg.
那时候它生着病，营养不良 还断了一条腿
But now, my trusty assistant...
而现在 我可靠的助手..
I mean, loving wife and colleague
我是说我的妻子兼同事
will  now release her back to her natural habitat.
就要把它放归回自然
It's okay, you can go now. Just like this.
都没事了 你可以走的 就像这样
Let me talk to her.
还是让我跟他说吧
Go on! Weirdos
走吧  怪咖
- Do you think she's gonna be okay? - Give her some time
-你觉得他会没事吗   -给他一点时间
Welcome home.
欢迎回家
Wait a minute. What she is saying, Tulio?
等一下 它..好像在说什么 图里奥
It's just difficult for her to say goodbye.
他是不舍得我们 在和我们说再见
No, I think she is trying to warn us.
不 我觉得他好像在警告我们
No no no, Linda,it might be some mating dance.
不不不 琳达 这可能是吸引异性的舞蹈
Tulio, look! Paddle!
图里奥 看那 快划 快啊
Okay, okay! Watch out!
好的 好的 小心
To the right ! No,no left
往后 往后 往右...不不不 往左
Forward! Forward!no,no,no backward
往前 往前 不 不 往后
Make up your mind, Tulio!
你想清楚再说 图里奥
Chese and sprinkles!
这下可糟了
Oh no! Paddle, Faster!
哦 不  快划快划 快点！
Tulio!
图里奥
Thank heavens you're ok.
感谢上帝 你没事
Tulio, is that a...
图里奥 这是..
Linda, this is incredible!
啊 琳达 真难以置信
《LET TAKE ME TO RIO》
Good moring, Jewel
早上好 珠儿
Hey everyone look what I found.
嘿 你们看我找到了什么
Blu ?
布鲁？
Kids?
孩子们？
Where everyone...
大家都去哪儿了？
Okay, who is ready for some Breakfast -Unbelievable.
-好了 谁肚子饿了想吃早饭   -难以置信
Did you know that these whole wheat pancakes
你知道么 那些全麦煎饼
Have twice the vitamins and minerals of regular pancakes?
所含的维生素矿物质是普通煎饼的两倍
And with the blueberries it's 4 times tasty.
而且加上蓝莓后味道会好上4倍
Hey,Where are the blueberries?
嘿 蓝莓都哪去了
Oh,dad, looking for this?
爸爸 你在找这个吗
Bring it!
给我吧
It's down to the final minutes, he's got magic in his feet
已经到了最后关头 他的脚仿佛有魔力一样
He shoots!
他射门了
Goal!
球进了！
Oh yeah, I got, I'm good.
噢耶 我接到了 我真是太棒了
Heads up, Dad.
爸爸 注意了
啊哦
Awsome!
哦 帅呆了
Hi, Mom!
嗨  妈妈
- Mom's mad. - Time to go.
-妈妈生气了  -该走了
Hi, honey. Are you hungry?
亲爱的 你饿了吗
Blu, we talked about this.
布鲁 我跟你说过的
Ummm,so,uhhh,so whatta you got there?
是吗 我不记得了 哦 对的 你拿的是什么
- Breakfast. - That's funny, but what is that?
-早饭  -很好笑 不过  说真的 这是什么
It's a Brazial nut
这是个巴西栗
I never thought I'd find one this close to the city.
离城市这么近的地方居然也有
- I want to show the kids how to open one. - You mean like this?
-我要教孩子们怎么打开  -你是说打开这个吗
Daddy already shown us.
爸爸已经教过我们了
Wait, go back.
等等 倒回去
Mom, Dad, you're on TV.
爸爸妈妈 你们上电视了
Doctor Tulio Monteiro,the"birdman"of Brazial
巴西鸟类学家图里奥蒙泰罗博士
announced an important discovery today
今天宣布了一项重大发现
We believe we have encountered a wild
我们相信 我们在亚马逊丛林深处找到了野生的
Blue Spix's Macaw Deep in the Amazon jungle
蓝色金刚鹦鹉
The blue  Spis's Macaw was thought practically extinct
蓝色金刚鹦鹉之前被认为在野外全部灭绝了
With the last remain famil
仅存的一家鹦鹉
living under  protection at the Blu Bird Sanctuary In Rio de Janeiro
目前居住在里约热内卢的布鲁鸟类保护区
We're famous
我们出名了
If where the birds are found
their home will be saved
如果找到这些野生鹦鹉 他们的家园将受到保护
There may be  a whole flock of birds out there
那里可能有很多这种鹦鹉
And if there is, we'll find them and protect them
如果真的有 我们会找到他们 并保护他们
Hi, Blu!
嗨 布鲁
Hi, Linda!
嗨 琳达
We are not the only one.
我们不是唯一的
There are more of us  there.
我们还有活着的同伴
-Yes, that's great.I'm sure there -All this time
-是啊 太好了 -这么长时间 我一直....
I thought we were all alone.
我一直以为...我们是孤独的
Hey,it wasn't been all bad
嘿 以前也没有那么糟糕
Of course not, but...
是挺好的 可是...
But just imagine there was a whole flock of us.
想象一下 有一大群同类
How amazing would that be!
那该有多么美妙啊
- We have to do something. - We do?
-我们得做点什么   -真的吗
Yeah, we have to fly to Amazon
对 我们去亚马逊
help Linda and Tulio find them.
去帮助琳达和图里奥找到他们
We can't  just pack up and go.
哦...我们不能说走就走
Why not? It's about me this family got a little air under our wings.
为什么不能 现在正是时候出去让翅膀吹吹风了
Look at us! IPod,TV, pancakes?
看看我们 音乐播放器 电视 煎饼
We are not people,we are birds
亲爱的 我们不是人类 我们可是鸟
We have to get out to thewild and be birds, Blu.
我们应该回到野外 做真正的鸟 布鲁
Let the kids conect their roots,
让孩子们叶落归根
show them what I had.
看看我们从前的生活
They need this, we need this
他们需要这样 我们也需要
Come on Blu! What do you say?
来吧，布鲁！你说呢？
I don't know. Maybe,...
我不知道...也许吧...
He didn't say no.
他没有说不
Which means he  practically said yes.
这就意味着他说 行
-hey,wait a second! - It's gonna be so much fun!
-嘿 等一下   -亲爱的，一定会很好玩！
We're going to the  Amazon.
耶...我们要去亚马逊咯
Wait, what is the Amazon?
等一下，亚马逊是什么？
The Amazon is one of the most threatened ecosystems
亚马逊，目前世界上最濒危的生态系统之一
Due to illegal deforestation and agriculture
由于非法砍伐和耕种
We hope the dr.Monteiro and his team
我们希望博士和他的团队
find these rare birds and save your home
能找到那些珍惜鸟类，让他们的家园得以保存
There may be  a whole flock of birds out there
那里可能有很多这种鹦鹉
If there is,we'll find them and protect them
如果真的有，我们会找到它们并保护他们
Tree huggers. Get my boat ready
环保狂 把我的船准备好
I need to take care of it personally.
我要亲自去处理这件事情
Next
下一个
That would be me. Ok,everyone can go home now
轮到我了，行了你们可以回家了
You are looking at the next King of Carnival.
你们正在看着的下一位，狂欢之王
Hi,big bird,break a leg!
嘿 大鸟 祝你好运
Ooooh, walk it off buddy.
别躺着 走两步
You can‘t see it coming
你不能发现它来到
You won't find anywhere else
也不能在其他地方寻找到
Bravo!
棒极了！
Bravo! That was amazing!
棒极了！你唱的真是太好了
Eve,darling, you hit every note.
我亲爱的，你刚才一个音符也没落下
-Huh,guys? -Yeah yeah,
-伙计们？  -对！是的！
with a bunch of notes I never heard of
还多了很多我从来没听过的音
- Raffi! - Don't worry!
-拉斐尔  -别 别担心
I'll talk to them.
我会和他们说的
We'll find a perfect spot for you!
我会为你找到完美的角色！
Antarctica maybe.
嗯...潜规则也没用(或许在南极洲)
You better! Bye bye!
最好如此 回头见
Ciao ciao bye, boys!
再见 孩子们！
See you back at home,my tasty mango!
我们家里见，我的美味小芒果
None of the acts are inspiring.I am just not inspired!
哎...这些表演一点都不好 我连一点灵感都没有
Carnival is right around the corner.
狂欢节眼看就要到了
And our reputations are on the line.
我们的名声会臭的
Copy that,we need something that can make us wiggle.
Something to make us jiggle.
明白！我们需要一些能让我们嗨起来的节奏
We need something pops pop pop pop pop
我们需要 火爆 火爆 火爆 火爆 火爆
You know what pop is backwards ?
知道倒过来怎么说吗
- Pop - Next.
爆火 下一个...
- Blu! - Sorry,Bro!
-布鲁  -对不起兄弟
It's Okay, Luiz! Good to see you too!
没关系 路易兹 我也很高兴见到你
Listen, Blu, we are looking for a singer
听着 布鲁 我们在寻找一位歌手
a dancer, the whole package.
一个舞者 样样都会的
Yeah and you're more of a mumbler-shuffer.you catch my drift?
不要唱歌跑调 跳舞摔跤的 你懂我的意思么？
No,no,no!I'm not here to aduition.
我不是来面试的
I've got news!
我有事情要宣布
I'm going to the Amazon.
我准备要去亚马逊了
Amazon!
亚马逊
That's wild.
那可真够野的
Yeah, Jewel thinks it will be good for us.
是呀 珠儿觉得这对我们有好处
- How wild? - Really wild.
-有多野  -超级野
They got mosquitoes that suck your blood like slurpess.
那里的蚊子能够一口吸干你的血
Snakes that can swallow you whole.
那里的蛇能一口将你整个吞下去
Flesh-eating pivanhas that eat...flesh.
那里还有吃肉的食人鱼 会吃肉的！
Oh,great, That's sounds really nice!
喔 好极了 看上去真不错
- I'm not going!  -Gus,guys,guys!
-我不去了   -得了伙计们
Blu ,you have nothing to worry about.
布鲁 你根本不用担心这些
All those stories are highly exaggerated.
他们说的这些都有点夸张的过分了
-You think so? -Of course
-你真的这么想？  -当然了！
If this important for Jewel,just do it.
如果这对珠儿很重要 那你就去吧
Happy wife,happy life
老婆开心 日子舒心
-Remember that -Ok,you're right.
-一定要记住   -好的 对！
You know,a little family vacation might actually be fun.
你说的对 就当全家一起去度假 一定很有趣
Plus,it's not like it's foever!
再说了 又不是定居在那里
That's the spirit.
这就对了
Yeah,ok, thanks guys!
好的 谢谢伙计们！
See you in a couple of weeks
几周后见
-safe travels, Blu! - Bring me back a souvenir!
-一路顺风 布鲁   -记得带纪念品回来
Dog, he won't be back.
得了 他不会回来了
He's dead.
他会死翘翘的
Amazon!
亚马逊！
Let's go!Come on! Come on, Dad!
我们走 快点爸爸 快点
Ok,bug spray,check Water purifier,cheak
Band-aids...
好的 驱虫剂 净水剂 还有创可贴
I feel like I'm forgetting something.
哦 我好像忘了点什么
Cool, the all-in-one Adventurer's knife.
哇哦 酷 是多功能探险者小刀
-I'll be in charge of this. -That's not for you!
这个还是给我保管吧 这不是给你的
Hey Dad, look at this!
嘿 爸爸 看看这个
Did you know the Amazon has snakes that can swallow you whole?
你知道亚马逊的蛇能一口把你吃掉吗？
Actually,Bia ,all those stories are highly exaggerated
事实上这些故事写得太夸张了
No, really! Look!
不一定吧 你看看
Oh,that's sick!
哦 这个好恶心啊
All right.We ready to go?
准备好出发了吗？
A fanny pack?
你带了个腰包？
Yeah,Linda gave to me, I need it for the GPS.
是的 琳达给我的 用来装GPS定位
Where is my GPS.
哦 我的GPS呢
Carla, we're leaving.
卡拉 我们要走啦
I'm not going! It's gonna be lame.
我才不去呢！肯定很无聊
Here it is the recognition voice makes everything easier.Look at this:
行了 找到了 它有语音识别功能 很好用的 你看着
Finding Linda and Tulio.
给我找琳达和图里奥
Searching for dinner in Tokyo
正在搜索 去东京吃晚餐
Ok,actually that is a good suggestion.
好的 额 事实上这个还真不错
- You trust this woman? - Yes, I do.
-你相信这个女人？  -是的 我相信
Hey hey Wait up family, I'm coming too.
嘿 等下伙计们 我们也要一起去
Do not worry.We protect you.
别担心哥们 我们会罩着你的
- Eva let you go? - Sure!
-你老婆让你去了吗？  -当然！
I promised her a spot in the carnival show.
我答应她在狂欢演出里给他弄个角色
- You did what? -You guys are late.
-答应他什么   -你们迟到了
-Clock late. - But musicians early.
-的确到晚了 -不过对于音乐家还早
Wait,you guys are coming?
等等 你们也要去吗？
We wouldn't miss it for the world.We're gonna scout the wildest coolest talent in that jungle.
我们当然不会错过 我们要去丛林寻找最棒的歌手
It's our inspit ration for this year's carnavival show.
这是我们今年狂欢节演出的创作灵感
Amazon untamed.
狂野亚马逊
Cool! I mean... Okay...
酷 我是说...好吧
I guess I'll go.
我也会去的
Amazon jungle for bust, baby!
去亚马逊放手一搏
Who's ready for a tropical adventure?
都准备好去热带探险了么
Guys, wait up!
等等 等等 孩子们 还没有点名
Recalculating
重新规划路线
Birds,go back!
嘿 小鸟 快回来
They were  without me again!
又是这样 丢下我自己走了！
太让人伤心了！
《O Vida》
里约热内卢
欧鲁普雷图
巴西利亚
Heavy traffic ahead
前方道路 拥堵
Thanks GPS lady.
多谢了 GPS小姐
Faster, faster!
快点 快点 快点
Slower!Slower!Slower!
慢点....
From Rio to Manace we're here in paridise
（歌词）从里约到玛瑙斯 我们到了天堂
Here we are, kids!The gate way to the Amazon.
我们到了孩子们，这里就是亚马逊的大门了
To be Not to be!
生存 还是....毁灭
That is the question!
这是个问题
究竟哪一个更高贵 去忍受这命运
还是去忍受着无边的烦恼
经受无边的摧残
还是把它忘个干净
Ah,that's beautiful, Nigel.What does it mean?
噢 真实太美妙了 奈杰尔 这是什么意思
Death, Gabi.
死亡 加比
It's about death.
说的是死亡
Oh,Nigel, I love it when you get all dark and brooding.
奈杰尔 我爱死你忧郁的沉思了
Bird, it's showtime!
嘿 笨鸟 该上场了
My audience awaits!
我的观众正等着我呢
From the streets of Rio to the Amazon jungle
从里约的丛林 到亚马逊的街头
The Mystery Bird.
有请 神秘的大鸟
Get that stock there.Back to work.
喂 别打蚂蚁的主意 干你的活去
Mom, I want this, I want a fortune!
妈妈 妈妈 我要玩这个 我要算命
Welcome,young lady.
欢迎光临 夫人
This amazing Cockatoo reveal your future.
这只难以置信的鹦鹉 能够预示你的未来
All right bird.rick a fortune.
好了小鸟 选一个吧
Come on bird!
快点 小鸟
You're doing great, Nigel.
你干的很好 奈杰尔
Pick it up.
快一点
Come on,almost there.No more flying today
加油 伙计们 就快到了 今天不用再飞了
We've got a boat to catch.
晚一点 我们能赶上一艘船
According this little friend we will get there in the morning.
根据这位小朋友的计算 明天一早我们就能到
You will survive, but will never fly
你能活下来 但永远也飞不起来了
- Come on! - I WANT MY FORTUNE
快点 小鸟 快给我算命
- You are doing great. -what's taking so long.
-很好奈杰尔  -怎么要这么长时间
The blue bird of my misery.
我会这么惨都是那只蓝色的鸟害的
Nice birdie.
小鸟乖
Why are you hitting yourself?
为什么要打自己 为什么要打自己
Nigel is very macho.
哇哦 奈杰尔好有男子汉气概
Thank you.
谢谢
I'm free!
我自由了
Poisonous frog!
这里有只箭毒蛙
The croaking cockatoo doth bellow  for revenge.
嘎嘎叫的凤头鹦鹉 呐喊着要去复仇
That's Shakespeare, by the way.
这是莎士比亚写得
-Without your performance,It'snothing. -That's great.
-没有你的表演 他一文不值   -说得好
GOOD TIME TO FINISH UP OLD TASKS
一个完成旧任务的好时机
This air,it's so fresh and full.
哦 这空气 又清新 又舒适
Goodbye,  city air!
再见了 城市里的雾霾
Yes,bye.
对！再见！
Hey,thank you for doing this.
I really appreciate it.
嘿 谢谢你能为我这样做 真的很谢谢你
I would do anything for you.
为了你 我愿意做任何事情
- You know that, right? - Of course I do.
-你懂得 对么？  -我当然懂
We are not come here to eat,
We came for revenge.
我们不是来这吃点心的 我们是来复仇的
When these passengers have flat sleeping
等那些讨厌的乘客们一睡着
let's give our  blue friends a little love.
我们就好好关爱下我的蓝色朋友们
Some poisonous love.
给他们来点有毒的爱
This is my specialty.
哦 这个我最拿手了
We will strike midnight,
because it looks like more evil.
我们在午夜发动攻击 这样显得更加邪恶
Stay alert.
保持警惕
Midnight. Time to attack!
午夜！袭击的时间
Nigel. Nigel.
奈杰尔 奈杰尔
Look at us,two criminals.
看我们 两个非主流
一只剧毒的青蛙 一只不会飞的怪鸟
So different and yet so alike
我们如此的不同 又如此的相同
My darling whilesleep all is well We're friends and that's swell
（歌词）亲爱的 当你睡着了 我们是朋友 那样很好
But the truth is that I have a secret to tell I love you
可是有个秘密一定要告诉你....我爱你
People say it is wrong and absurd
a frog and a bird are in love
《Poisonous Love》
你是我的罗密欧 我是你的朱丽叶
What a nightmare.
好可怕的梦
Charli, was you should have woken me up.
查理 你应该把我叫醒的
It's time for revenge.
要行动了
I love being on team with Nigel.
能做奈杰尔的搭档真好
I can't think of any thing more romantic
我想不出什么比在夜晚下
than poisoning passengers on a moonlight cruise
给乘客下毒更浪漫的事情了
Stop!
住手
This one is mine.
那家伙是我的
Twinkle, twinkle, little Blu.
How I wondered where were you?
一闪一闪小布鲁...找你找得好辛苦...
Up above the world so high.
高高的挂在天空中...
Are you ready to die?
今天让你..一命呜呼
You need a TicTac.
你应该吃块绿箭薄荷糖
Even in sleep you mock me?
你睡着了都要嘲笑我！
Wait for me.
等等我
Do not leave me!
别丢下我
-Tiago, stop fooling around.
- I didn't do anything.
-提亚戈 别到处乱跑  -我什么也没干啊
Tiago Gunderson, listen to your mother.
提亚戈・甘德森 听妈妈的话
Oh man.
哦 天啊
-We're almost there. -Hey guys wait up.
-我们快到了  -等一下伙计们
Remember... Birds of blue ...fine.
记住 有蓝色....算了
They are geting away.
他们都跑了
Wake up, you insect-eating idiot Follow them!
快醒醒你这个吃虫子的笨蛋 跟着他们
Better!Now go ten times faster!
好多了 现在给我再快10倍
河猪
我一直在想 你是不是比猴子还笨
And now I know.
现在我懂了
boss, what are you doing in the jungle?
老板 您来丛林里干什么？
Perhaps the better question is:
What are they doing?
你应该问他们来这里干什么
Tree hugger.
那些环保狂
这里有几百万平方英里的丛林
可替他们偏偏跑到这里来
我可不是好惹的家伙
As you know,my friends, this deforestation
你也知道 朋友 我们的伐木作业
is a little... illegal.
稍微有点....违法
If these two crazy find think those birds
如果这些人找到那些鸟 我们的生意就完了
所以你现在要尽快结束他们的寻鸟丛林探险
Find them! And get rid of them
找到他们 赶走他们
The rest of you,go cut some trees.
其余的人 都给我砍树去
Who cares a flock of birds?
谁在乎一群什么破鸟
金刚鹦鹉会把巢筑在巴西栗树附近
I think we should continue...
所以我觉得我们应该...
Tulio, are you listening?
图里奥 你在听我说话吗
You have reached your destination
你已到达目的地
You see? It worked,like a charm. Here we are.
看见吧 她很管用吧 到了
Where?
这是哪？
These things have a margin of error
嗯 这东西稍微有点误差
I told you not trust this woman.
我跟你说过别相信那个女人
Ohh,that's a Heliconius larva.It feeds on roting fruit
那是葭蝶的幼虫 它就要进入蛹的阶段
哈 你说桶
-hey kids stay close. -I'll get them.
-你们跟紧了  -我要去找他们
Okay, you guys stay here and I'll look around.
好吧 你们留在这里别动 我去周边看看
Do not worry, we'll be here.We're not going anywhere.
别担心 我们就在这 我们哪儿都不去
-My feathers is poppin'up on the back ofmy neck.
-I don't like this.
我后背的羽毛都竖起来了 我可不喜欢这个感觉
Let's back it up.
我们调头吧
Bia?Tiago!
比亚 迪耶戈
Come on lady, don't let me down.
拜托 小姐 别让我失望
Calculating route to:
规划前往...秀场的路线
Great
好吧 太好了
Okay, guys...
伙计们？
Good one, guys. Very funny.
呵呵 可以 这很好玩
Funny same. Very clever.
很好很好 很聪明
Jewel, where are you?
珠儿 你在哪？
Kids? Jewel?
孩子们  珠儿？
It's a macaw!
啊 金刚鹦鹉 琳达！
Let me go! You barian.
放开我 你这个野蛮人
Blu?
布鲁？
I swear that sound like Blu.
我发誓 这声音听起来像布鲁的
It's impossible, Linda.
不 不可能 琳达
He is  back home in Rio safe and sound.
他在家里 既舒适又安全
I am an americian citizen,you savage!
我可是美国公民 你这个野蛮人
I demand to see my ambassador.I know my rights
我要求见美国大使 我知道我有这个权利
I know my rights.
我有这个权利
Back you barian.
退后 野蛮人
That's right.Is a spoon and a fork.
对 没错 这是个勺子 也是个叉子
Be afraid. Be very afraid.
害怕了吧 怕的发抖了吧
Boddy, put the spork down.
哥们 把你的叉勺放下
Let me go .
放开我...有种来啊 要不是你运气好 我就跟你...
I can not believe we found them.
真不敢相信 我们找到他们了
Well, technically,they found us.
严格的说 是他们找到了我们
Ok,we're going to need some name tags.
好吧 给他们点写名字的牌子
Those are Tic Tacs.
哦 那个是薄荷糖
Not that you need one,but they are good.You eat them.
你用不到它 不过味道还不错...你可以试试
No,no,no,no,no,no, not the whole box.
不 别连盒都吞下去
Get that out of your mouth .
赶快..把它..吐出来
What is this doing here?What is going on?
出什么事情 怎么了？
We found them flying too  close to humans.
我们发现他们飞得离人类太近
What?and  Who are you?
什么 你是谁？
Uh is not an appropriate answer.I asked you a question.
额 可不是一个合适的回答 我问你话呢
Where are you from?
你们到底从哪来
-Hey  back off.
- Excuse me, young lady. That...
嘿 退后 你干什么 不好意思小姐...
I can't believe it.
真不敢相信
How... How is this...
这...这怎么可能
When humans came.
伐木工来的时候到处都是大火
There was so much smoke and fire.
到处都是浓烟 然后...
I had you under my wing.
我把你藏在翅膀下面
And then you were -Gone
然后你就...不见了
I looked for you everywhere.
-我一直在找你   -我在这
Daddy.
爸爸
Daddy?
爸爸？
I missed you.
我好想你
It's Okay. Now everything is fine.
没事了 一切都过去了
Daddy has you.
有爸爸在
Look at you. It's my little girl.
看看你 我的小女儿
All grown up.
已经长大了
You're so beautiful.
长得这么漂亮
Just like your mother.
就像你的妈妈一样
I'm sorry I lost you.
对不起 我把你弄丢了
I can't imagine you alone this whole time.
我无法想象这些年 你孤孤单单的...
It's okay, Dad. I was not alone.
没什么 爸爸 我不孤单
Blu found me.
布鲁找到我了
It's nice to meet you sir.
很高兴见到你 先生
Tuck that wing away,Stu.Now come here.
把翅膀收起来 布鲁 到我这来
- ok. - Closer.
-当然     -近一点
- Really? - Closer.
-是吗？   -再近点
You brought my Jewel back.
你把我女儿带回来了
I thank you.
我谢谢你
I'm going to hug you now.
现在我要拥抱你
Okay.
额 好的
- Come here.- That's it.
-行了 过来吧   -抱上了
It's my pleasure.
真是我的荣幸
Nico you crying?
什么 你在哭吗？
It's a heavy moment and I'm very rnlnerable right now.
看到这么感人的场面 我内心很脆弱啊
Come here,let me get you a hug.
拥抱吧 我们
Mom, are you okay?
妈妈 你没事吧
Mom ? I'm a Grandpa.
妈妈？我当外公了
I'm a Grandpa.
我当外公了
Look at me, I'm a Grandpa!
看看我 我当外公了
Daddy, this Carla Bia and Tiago.
爸爸 这是卡拉 碧雅 提亚戈
-Nice to meet you, sir.
- There is no sir, young lady.
-你好呀 先生   -不要叫我先生 我的小姐
-You'll call me papa.- Pa Pa? I like that.Sounds good.
-你们叫我Pa Pa -Pa Pa ？我喜欢
I'm papa, papa.
我是外公啦 太好啦  我是外公啦
Kids,go easy on old papa.
别把外公弄伤了 孩子们
You call me sir.
你还是叫我先生
My daughter has returned.
我女儿回来啦
For years we live because humans fleeing push us
这些年我们东躲西藏 人类把我们逼往
more to the forest.
越来越深的丛林
But as you can see we found a sanctuary.
不过你看 我们找到了一个避难所
A place where finally fincamos roots
我们终于可以在这里扎根了
Everyone. Come out.
大伙们 出来吧
My daughter is back.
我女儿回来啦
My Jewel returned.
出来吧小鸟们  我的珠儿回来啦
Jewel ?
珠儿？
Make way,make way.Jewel!
让开  让开 珠儿！
Aunt Mimi? Aunt Mimi.
咪咪婶婶  咪咪婶婶
I missed you so much.
哦 我想死你了
My little wild flower has returned.
我的小野花终于回家了
I know you'll be back.
我就知道你会回来
I saw the specks of poop.
我会用鸟粪算命
Look at these puppies.
看看这些小家伙们
谁是毛茸茸的 最可爱的的小金刚鹦鹉
This is a big boy for your age.
哦 你长得可有点着急啊
Mimi, this is the Stu.
哦 咪咪婶 这是苏
Actually I am  Blu.
事实上我叫布鲁
-So am I dear - oh,no,that's my name.
-我们都是鹦鹉 呵呵   -我叫布鲁 蓝色的意思
We're all blue dear.That's why they called us blue macaws
我们都是蓝色的，
这就是为什么我们叫蓝金刚鹦鹉
just go with it.
你就依着她吧
《Welcome Back》
So that's what a blue macaw is supposed to look like?
原来你在这种鸟里长得算是挫的
Roberto, I...
罗伯特....我
Welcome back
欢迎回来
- You are beautiful. - So do you.
-哇 你看上去棒极了   -你也是
Hey, hi, hello.
I am Jewel's significant other.
嗨 你好 我是珠儿的...重要的那一位
So you're the lucky bird who swept Ju-Ju of her feet
哦 那你就是那个俘获了珠珠放心的幸运鸟
-Ju-Ju? -yeah
-珠珠？  -是啊
When we were kids we always
had the cutest names for each other.
我们小时候一直给对方起可爱的小名
We did.I called him Beto.
是啊 我叫他 贝托
This is lovely.I Love apelidinhos.
那真可爱 我也喜欢起小名
You never mentioned any Roberto.
你可从来没提起过什么罗伯特
There was nothing to mention.
那是他没有什么可提的啊
There is my wing man.
哎...我的搭档来了
有罗伯特放哨 我们都能安心睡觉了
Eduardo taught me everything I know.He is the bird.
-对亏了爱德华多教我   -他是一只好鸟
No, you're the bird.
-不 你是只好鸟   -不 你才是好鸟...
We get it.You're both the birds.
知道了 你们两个都是好鸟
Now stop  yapping and start the party
能不能别唧唧哇哇了 开始聚会吧
《Beautiful Creatures》
I remember this song.
哇哦...我记得这首歌
How could you forget?
It's in our blood baby.
怎么可能忘记 它一直流淌在我们的血液里
It's who we are.
这是只属于我们的歌
You don't mind if I borrow her for a minute,do you
不介意我借用她一会吧？嗯...
-Actually... - Let's go Ju-Ju.
-额 事实上我...   -来吧 珠珠
Let's come together, singing love and harmonia
We are so different, but the same inside our hearts
Beautiful colors, as far as the eyes can see ya
Open your wings, fly when you hear the call
Let's celebrate, calling the beautiful creatures
Come spread your wings dance and sing songs about freedom
Like lah lah lah hoo hoo
One for the jungle familia
Like bah bah bah boo boo
Calling the beautiful creatures
Come this way celebrate
Laugh and dance all the way
-这个地方真是潜力无穷啊  -我好喜欢他们这种歌
Follow me sing along
Lah lah bah bah boom boom...
Ja disse que Jade chegou
Ja disse que ja disse que Jade chegou...
Pop-pop, I am the pop-pop
I am the tchh I am your pop-pop
I am the pop-pop-pop, tchch pop-pop-pop
I am the pop-pop the tchhhchhc
Let's celebrate, calling the beautiful creatures
Come spread your wings,dance and sing songs about freedom
Like lah lah lah hoo hoo
One for the jungle familia
Like bah bah bah boo boo
Calling the beautiful creatures
You're the only one who knows what it feels like to be all alone
只有你能理解 孤苦伶仃是什么感觉
Misunderstood.You're evil to my lethal
总被误解 你邪恶 我狠毒
I can see why they call you Gabi
你该改个名叫话痨
Where are you,you filthy fowl
在哪儿呢 你这个肮脏的家禽
Halt
停下
I've been going about this all wrong
我之前的行动战略不对
Ineed to be a higher ground
我应该去更高的地方找
You stayed air borne for almost a fuul second that time
哦 你刚才腾空了将近整整一秒钟
真是太厉害了
What are you looking at?Get up there
你看什么看 帮我上去
Higher
高点
even higher
再高点
little bit higher
稍微再高点
Lower,lower now.Yes.Perfect
低点 现在低点 很好 现在正好
Ugh,it's an infestation
哇哦 这么一大群祸害
Keep celebrating,I'll be pooping on your party pronptly.
呵呵 继续庆祝吧 你们很快就要高兴不起来了
Hi,Nico,hi,Pedro
嗨 尼科  嗨 派卓
We came to the right place
我们来对地方了 这就是火爆 亚马逊的火爆
We can bring these macaws back to Rio
我们要把这些金刚鹦鹉带回里约
And have the best carnaval show ever.I'm inspired.
参加有史以来最棒的狂欢节演出 我现在灵感如泉涌
Sorry to break it to you city boys
抱歉 城里来的鸟
But you'll have to find some other talent
我看你们还是去找别的明星吧
Nobady leaves the tribe
谁也不许离开这里
Oh,and no human things in the jungle,
哦 还有 丛林里不许留下人类的东西
understood
听懂了么
What?What's his problem
什么 他什么毛病
I feel naked
我被扒光了...
We coulda been legends
差点就能流芳百世了
I mean we already are supermega dope ,
but you koow what I'm saying
我们已经超级无敌赞了 可是...你懂我的意思吗
We had it all
什么都有了
The undiscovered talent,the big idea and the inspiration
没被发掘的明星 好的创意
But if we can't bring these guys to Rio
可是没有办法把他们带回里约...
We got nothing
就什么都没有
Nothing?
什么都没有？
hold your mangoes,we still have Eva
别那么失落,我们还有伊娃
What?
怎么
Wow,you still got the moves Ju-Ju
哇哦 你跳的还是那么好 珠珠
Oh my gosh,I havn't danced ke that forever
Yeah,we should get some rest
-我快累死了   -是啊 我们该去休息了
Find a local inn or B&B nearby
是啊,我们该去休息了
找家当地旅馆,或是民宿
What is this crazy talk
你在胡说些什么啊
Now,you guys are staying in my nest
不 你们就住我家里
I'm on patrol tonight
今晚我巡逻
My house is your house -That's really nice Beto
-我的家 就是你们的家   -你真是太好了贝托
Thank you but we're fine
谢谢 但我觉得我们能搞定
Besides,our whole family couldn't possibly fit in your bachelor pad
再说我们一大家子 住单身公寓 挤不下
哇哦
Real estate must be pretty cheap around here
这里的房价一定非常低吧
哇哦 真是不可思议
Oh,this old nest.It's just something I put together last minute
你说这家？这只是我最近随便弄的
With my own two wings,of course
当然 用的是我的两只翅膀
And my strengh.And my brawn
我的力气 还有我的肌肉
Dad,It's huge!it has six bedrooms!
爸爸 这里好大 有六个卧室呢
I get the big one -No,I'm the oldest
-我要最大的这间  -不行 我是老大
Only by three minutes two point five seconds.
就比我大3分钟外加2.5秒
I had hoped to one day be blessed with a flock of little Robertos to call my own
我真希望有一天也能有一群小罗伯特在这里抢房间
I bet you did -A birdbath!yeah
-一定会的   -不会吧 这里还有鸟浴盆
还有按摩
Listen Blu
嘿 布鲁 我告诉你
if anything,and I mean anything,ever happens to you
如果你出了任何事 任何
I'll take care of your family
我会帮忙照顾好你的家人
Sleep well
行了 睡个好觉
-Good night Ju-Ju -Good night
-晚安 珠珠   -晚安
All clear
好了 一切都安全了
《Don't Go Away》
Moonbeams and starlight Magical twilight
The warmest rain Hear it whispering your names
（歌词）月光和星光 神奇的曙光 最温暖的雨 听他低吟你的名字
Rainbows at midnight Sparkling night skies
Don't go away Stay another day
午夜的彩虹 让星空闪耀 不要远走 多停留一天
Can you sing it more time please
你能再唱一遍吗？
Time for bed now
该睡觉了
What an amazing day
多棒的一天啊
All this time,
一直以来 我...
I never let myself hop they were still alive
我都没奢望过他们还活着
But...but they are
但是他们真的还都活着
We found our family Blu,
我们找到家人了 布鲁
This changes everything
这会改变一切的
Yeah.
是的
Wait,what? Waht's changing
等等 什么？ 改变什么？
Jewel
珠儿
去 去  走开
Honey ,stop it's ticklish
亲爱的 别 别这样 很痒的
That was fun
哈哈 真有意思
提亚戈
Let's go
快走 迪耶戈 看我们走
Good moring,
早上好
what should I say good afternoon
或者我应该说 下午好
Moring sir
早上好 先生
Our day in the jungle started early
生活在这里得习惯早起
Moring dad
早上好 爸爸
That's my girl,already up and at'em
真是我的好女儿 她早就起来了
Moring sweete
早上好 亲爱的
Why did you let me sleep in
你干嘛然我睡懒觉
What are you talking about You sleep in every day
你说什么呢？你每天都睡懒觉
Yeah,but...      Hey Dad,
-是的 可是...   -爸爸
Aunt Mimi says clay is good for your digestion
咪咪阿姨说泥土对消化有好处
Try some -Oh no honey.I've brushed my-
-你试试   -不 亲爱的 我刚刷完-
It's good right?I'm gonna go get some more
味道不错吧 我再去弄点
Smart girl
聪明的孩子
So i thought I'd tke Stu here for a little tour of the area Show him around
我说要领格鲁转一转 参观一下
Oh,that's a great idea -What
-这主意太好了  -什么？
You go have fun with Daddy and I'll explore around here with the kids
你跟爸爸出去转转 我带孩子们探探险
Oh,oh,yeah,ok
-恩 好的   -你会喜欢的
Yeah,great,I just gotta-
恩 好的  我只要...
Ok,ready
行了  好了
Ok,Stu,come here
行了 lu 靠近点
Not so close
-太近了   -好的
Listen
听着...
I can't see it anymore You gotta lose that human pocket,ok?
我看不下去了 你把人类的口袋扔掉 行吗？
Oh,this a fanny pack
这只是个腰包
Fanny pack?It's Cute
腰包 很可爱
But it's human's
但这是人类的
And you've enter the flock
现在你已经是部落的一员了
You wouldn't need it any longer
你以后用不着它了
I'll meet you by the clay banks
我们在河边泥岸上见
Enter the flock
哦 不 加入部落？
他不会以为我们真要搬到丛林里来吧
No,no,he'sso excited because we're here
不 不 他是因为我们来了 太激动了
别扫兴好么
It won't kill you to leave behind the fanny pack
再说了 不带这个腰包去又不会要了你的命
Ok,you win
好吧 你赢了
我不带腰包就是了
Happy wife,happy life
老婆高兴 日子舒心
Bye honey haeve fun
再见 亲爱的 玩的开心点
Yeah,sure,bye
哦 当然 再见
Gus,wakey,wakey
各位 该起床了
Wake up!
起床啦！
Eva,you got it
伊娃 你有角色了
What happened on Amazon untapped?
那个也行亚马逊怎么样了？
Here's my plan,
我定了计划
odition today And we have a show tomorrow
今天面试 然后明天预演一场
We,you said we,you speak French
我们？什么 你在说法语么？
Come on,chap,chap,let's starting
行了 赶紧的 我们开始吧
She's so fast
哇哦 她动作可够快的
Anytime when you ready
准备好了就可以开始了
每次碰见个男的 我就想把他追到手
可是他们最后都逃走了 我就装傻 我就装酷
管他们想什么 做什么
我不关心 到此结束
Next!    -We're
-下一个  -我们是
the amazing dance turtle
神奇的巴西战舞龟
Bravo! Another one! Another one!
太精彩了 再来一个 再来一个
Got ! Did I miss something?
抱歉 伙计们 刚才谁表演
Hi my name is Clare, the capybara
嘿 我叫克莱啦 我是水豚
And I'll sing my favorite song
我要唱一首我最喜欢的歌
回忆
孤零零的站在月光里
告诉我
离开是如此的容易
If you keep eating if there is no show.
再这么吃下去我们就没有演员了
This is not a food contest.
这里不是比谁吃的多
Oh,hey,you're fast .You're really fast
嘿 你飞的好快 真的好快
I think I pulled a wing or something, you is fast for his age.
我感觉我翅膀已经拉伤了 你这老鸟飞的还真快
For such a wise...wise
我是说...你的智慧
a wise bird.
智慧 拥有很多智慧的鸟
Wise is what I meant to say wise bird
which sometimes comes with age
智慧一般是随年龄一起增长的
But also can happen when you're young like you in your case You can be wise and young
不过年轻的时候也增长 比如像你 年轻又智慧
Which is kind of a rare combination
But thrilling when it happens
这种组合很少见 不过看到你真的好让人激动
- Be quiet. - OK, sir.
-安静点儿   -好的 先生
It's time to take the city of you.
你应该把城市的习惯丢掉了
You need to learn the basic skills of jungle
你要学习基本的...丛林生存要素
I thought we were sightseeing
我们不是出来观光的吗？
I'll give you some special trianing
我要给你做特训
Come on! Nud is your friend.
来吧 泥土是你的朋友
That is their camouflage. Feel it, Taste it.
这是你的伪装 感觉他 品尝他
如果没感觉 说明你的动作不对
You don't want to be seen by humans.
你不会想被人类看见的
Come on,are you a macaw or a turkey?
快点儿 你是蓝皮克斯鹦鹉还是火鸡？
Faster! Faster!
快点 再快点
Come on!you don't want to be eaten.
加油！你不想被吃掉吧
You're alone in the jungle
You get caught in trap
你独自一人在丛林里 你被陷阱抓住了
What do you do?
你会怎么办？
Well,if I had my fanny pack... -no
-如果我的腰包在的话  -不
-no,you use youe beak!
- My beak!
-你要用你的喙   -我的喙？
It's your most important tool.
这是你最重要的工具
Okay, I use my beak.
好的 我用我的嘴
- Almost. - Time's up.
-就差一点了   -时间到
You died.
你死定了
Roberto got it on the first try.
罗伯特第一次就成功了
Of course he did
肯定的
Up, Up,and hoover!Hoover
上 上 盘旋
Now Backwards!
现在倒着飞
Backwards? Only hummingbirds can fly bakwards.
倒飞？什么 不 只有蜂鸟能倒着飞
Backwards.
倒着飞
Under! Over! Under! Over!
跳  飞起来 俯冲 在高点
- Good job! - Oh,thanks.
-干得好   -谢谢
Not you.
没说你
The Brazial nut trees.
这是巴西栗树
These trees are the key to our survival
这些树对我们的生存至关重要
The tree, feed us, sustain us
这些树为我们提供食物 它们供养我们
They...
他们...
Wake up!
醒醒
I'm up! I'm up Nut Brazil,
我醒着 我醒着呢 栗巴西
Brazial unt.
Oh,got it
哦 不 巴西栗什么的 哦 明白了
This is important.
这很重要
We have to protect these trees.
我们要保护这些树
Our future depends on it.
我们的未来要依靠他们
Edie, who's your sidekick?
嗨 艾迪 这跟班是谁啊
You got a nurse now
你现在需要护士了？
- Hi, I'm... - aren't you boys
-嗨 我是...   -你们是不是
Geting a little too close to our side?
离我们的地盘太近了？
We have a deal, Felipe.
我们说好的 费利佩
Relax!you know we got nothing but mad love for you
嘿 别紧张 你知道我们对你满怀深情
Come on, guys, let's fly,
来吧 伙计们快飞吧
paint the skies,let them start to cry.
给天空添些色彩吧 让他们去哭鼻子咯
-they seem nice. - they have their side
-他们挺和气的   -树林那边是他们的
and we have ours.
这边是我们的
The food is scarce.
最近食物很少
Never seen them so close to the village.
从没看见他们离我们的家园这么近
- Do not let them see you. - Sure, sorry.
-别让他们看到你   -哦 对 抱歉
Maybe we should go find Linda.
也许我们应该去找琳达
- What is Linda? - Linda is the person...
-那是什么？  -琳达是人
- who created me. - What?
-她把我养大   -什么？
- you are a pet - No, no,
-你是宠物？  -不 不
is not what you think, I was a companion.
不是你想的那样 我们是朋友
Compaion?
什么？ 朋友 哦
That explains all things.
哦 难怪你这副样子
- Linda is my family. - Family?
-琳达是我的家人  -家人？
Humans are not family.
人类不是我们的家人
You do not understand, they came to help.
你没明白 他们是来帮忙的
Listen, do not bring human to the tribe.
听我说 绝对不能带人类来我们的部落
Stay away humans is why are still alive.
远离人类我们才活到现在
这你总应该明白吧
Understood?
你明白了吗？
Got it.
是的 明白
Sightseeing is over.
现在 观光结束
Tlio did you see the nest?
你看见鸟巢了吗？
Tulio,are you okay?
图里奥 你没事吧？
Yes, I'm fine,I'm ok
我没事 我很好 我...
I'm not...ok.
我不太好
Tulio they're cutting the forest!
图里奥 他们在砍伐森林
-LInda where are you going? -To  talk to them.
-琳达你要去哪？  -去和他们说
You talk yo birds I talk to humans
你去跟鸟说 我去和人说
No, wait!Don't
不 等等
Hey,hey,mister!
嘿 先生 你好
Hello?You take it easy with that chain saw.
我命令你把电锯关掉
There are rare birds living around here.
有很珍贵的鸟类居住在这片丛林里
You can't cut down those trees!
你不能把这些树都砍掉
Oh,sweetheart,there you are
哦 亲爱的 你在这儿啊
I was looking for you.
我到处找你
Beautiful out of  here, isn't it?
嗨 你好 这儿真漂亮 对吗？
You two are lost?
你们迷路了？
Lost? No!
迷路？ 没有 呵呵 迷路？
We are here on our honeymoon.
我们是来 来 来度蜜月的
We're actually just heading back to join the tour
我们正要回去和旅行团汇合呢
It's karaoke night.
今天晚上 有一场卡拉ok
Come on, dear,let's go. .
走吧 亲爱的 人家还等着我们去唱..月亮河呢
Linda,logs aren't the only things these guys cut.
琳达 这些人砍得可不止这些树
Run! Linda I'll pulll them. Go! Go!
快跑 琳达 我拖住他们 快跑！
Excuse me.
请让一下
Come on ,let's race.
来吧 我们来比赛
- Cool! - Good, Tiago.
-真是太棒了  -好样的 提亚戈
Tiago!
提亚戈
哦 太爽了
Hey,you are back.
嘿 你们回来啦
How was it going?
玩儿的怎么样啊？
We had a great fun.It was educational.
我们玩的很开心 今天很有教育意义
Dad, Uncle Bito taught me Some cool tricks.
爸爸 贝托叔叔教我一些很酷的飞行技巧
- Uncle? - Look, I can fly backwards.
-叔叔？  -看 我会倒着飞啦
是啊 你很有天分 小雷鸟
It's Never too late to learn
the forest life
丛林的生活技巧要从小学起
Someone may never learn.
可是有些家伙学不会
I'm going to clean up.
我要去..洗个澡
Roberto,I saw human near the jungle.
罗伯特 我看见人类在丛林附近
We need to beware.
你要保持警惕
丛林的生活方法..我倒想学离开的方法
There he is.Now is our chance.
哦 他在那儿 我们的机会来啦
I'm so happy!
哦 我真是太激动了
Prepare the tongue-a-bult.
准备舌头弹弓
Charli,make me fly again.
查理 让我重新飞起来
Take it, tiger.
去干掉他们 老虎
Bow before the conquering cockatoo!
快向征服你的凤头鹦鹉跪拜吧
What is your problem, man?
你是不是有病啊 伙计？
That was sick.
天哪 好变态啊
That's the energy you bring to an audition
我说 面试的时候就该有这种镜头
Audition?
面试？
Yeah,thats actually why I'm here.
I've got a greatlittle...
是啊 我就是面试的 我有一个很棒的....
Go on.
您继续
We are looking for a new star.
我们在寻找一个新的明星
Star?
明星？
You look familiar.
你看上去很眼熟
Don't I know you from somewhere?
我们是不是哪儿见过？
No, I don't think so
不 不 不会的
I am...Bob.
我叫...鲍勃
Yes,Bob the bird.
对 鲍勃 小鸟鲍勃
Ok,show us what you got.
无所谓啦 展示才艺吧
Well,when I first, I was afraid
恩 一开始我很害怕
I was petrified.
我惊得目瞪口呆
I kept thinking that I could never live
我一直以为我没法再活下去
I could barely fly.
没法再展翅飞翔
And I spend oh so many nights thinking
我在无数个慢慢长夜里回想
How he did me wrong
回想起他对我的残忍
And I grew strong.
于是我变得坚强
And I learned how to get along
我学会了如何随遇而安
Go on,now go
走吧 快滚
《I Will Survive》
Walk out the door
滚出这扇门
Just turn around now
转身离开吧
It's I who have the floor
现在这里是我的了
was not you who tried hurt me with goodbye
你不就是那个想用分手来伤害我的人吗？
Did you think I'd lay down and die
-你以为我会垮掉  -哦 不
你以为我会躺在这儿死掉？
-不 奈杰尔你不会  -我会活下来
只要我知道怎么去恨 我就会活下来
我会好好过这一生
我又满腔的爱要付出
-我会活下来  -你会活下来
-我会活下来  -我们会活下来
我是个幸存者 我的眼睛虎视眈眈
加强修炼 多吃高纤
你只是活着 而我是鲜活的活着
你要坐稳了 我吐口水的时候声音响彻云霄
你从来没见过一只凤头鹦鹉
随着摇滚的节奏 又唱又跳 尽情摇摆
看看我的本事 都用不着调音器
怎么样
真的没有用哦
如果你你打压我
只会让我变得更坚强
你想打断我
只会让我说的更多
如果你想用乒乓球打败我
我会变成乒乓球健将
给我个王位 我准备好上位
我很清楚 我会活下去
我会...
活下去
谢谢 我是小鸟 鲍勃
他真是太帅了
-好了 就是他 我要了   -虽然不如伊娃 但是你很棒
明天晚上狂欢节演出的时候见
这里所有的鸟都会来看
你一定会红到发紫的
所有鸟
这是个完美的计划
算你运气好 拔你几根刺 豪猪
滚吧
与其满林子追那只鸟
不如让他演出的时候自己送上门
我会在舞台上迷住他们
而在观众席里 你 我的小噶比...
你会成为我的 迷你致命武器
这场演出将会是..
好看到死
只有我才笑得出那种气场
好的 爱你哦
啊...舒服
好耶
哦 亲爱的 你在这儿 怎么这么长时间？
啊 别再弄那个GPS了
我们一起去看日落 快走吧
等一下 我刚找到琳达和图里奥的坐标
他们就在林子的另一半 瞧
他们离得很近
是呀 我知道你爸爸不相信人类
可他一旦见到了 他就会改变想法
琳达他们能保护这里
是的 布鲁 我爸自己能解决
我说你能不能忘掉琳达和图里奥一会儿
好好享受日落？
但是这不是我们的计划吗？
GPS:路线规划完成
恩...我...
你知道 有些地方也许不该被发现
也许就应该与世隔绝
她吃了一只虫子 一只虫子
布鲁 布鲁 冷静
冷静？我们有个计划
帮助琳达和图里奥找到鹦鹉 然后回家
可是我提醒他 她根本就不理我
哦 还有他的爸爸
他就是个疯子 他对人类的看法很奇怪
他对人类的看法很奇怪
他爱人类 他是个宠物
宠物？
他叫我宠物！
真不敢相信 他居然当我的面这么说
像是把我当成敌人似的
他跟我们不是一路的 你要盯着点儿他
还有那个罗伯特 他在监视
总是在珠儿身边转 总是唱着什么歌
我根本比不上他
你要拿出点鸟样来 从被驯养的状态中解放出来
用珠儿的眼光看这里
去尝尝珠儿品尝的那些味道
让我去吃虫子？
那太恶心了 再考虑一下
-闪光片 我的闪光片在哪儿？  -哦 对不起 对不起
我不需要听道歉 我要闪光片
充满魔力的表演最终要靠的就是闪光片
你怎么就不懂呢？
伙计们 快去彩排 明天是个大日子
想起来了吗？ 来吧 你来吗 爸爸？
哦 当然了
那孩子把娱乐搞得像是交作业
-布鲁 记住   -我知道 我知道了
老婆开心 日子舒心
多么美好的晨曦啊！
我都忘记了能够享受这样的早晨
你最爱吃的
哦 你记得这个 这样多好啊
这感觉真是好极了 谢谢你 布鲁
对呀
我要给珠儿一个惊喜 给他送早餐 马上就来
巴西栗 你们在哪儿？
我就知道你们在这附近
不 快回来 等等
-那不是玩具  -GPS:违章驾驶 靠边停车
不 不 不要
抓到你了
总算找到了 巴西栗
这个才是我最重要的工具
好啊 好啊 瞧瞧这是谁来了
看样子不是所有的鸟都遵守老艾迪的规矩
这儿是我们的地盘
哦 是吗？ 对不起 我没注意到 真抱歉
对不起 对不起
闯进我们的地盘 抢我们的食物
现在你还侮辱我？
不 不 不 这件事儿完全是个误会
知道吗 我非常想接受你的道歉
你看上去像是只好鸟 可是这代表战争！
什么？有必要吗？能代表点别的吗？
今天 在死亡坑
对不起 死亡坑 真的吗？
-哦 真的   -正午 我要腾出点地方来
像扫帚一样把你扫出这片林子
-你干了什么？   -那是个意外
-意外  -嘿 出了什么事？
多谢布鲁 我们可能要失去这片林子了
我只是想去摘个坚果  就一个
你都不喜欢吃坚果 这到底是怎么一回事 布鲁？
我想给你准备点早餐
哦 真的吗？
罗伯特 你带上最棒的鸟去
我们绝不能不战而降
明白
你 别管这事儿了 净添麻烦
-等等   -布鲁 他是对的
就让爸爸和罗伯特去处理这件事吧
-你也觉得我处理不了？  -不 我只是...
只是不太确定 外交在不在你的专长范围内
快走  快走 死亡坑
无线电！
我希望你别介意 我把这儿当自己家
棒棒糖？
真是可惜啊 你们两位大老远跑来保护这片森林
我们看看它会不会报答你们
两个疯子...
-罗伯特   -费利佩
给他点厉害瞧瞧
-我得阻止他们  -什么 布鲁？
停下 停下 艾迪 这太疯狂
我们是高等物种 我们能更好的解决问题
这是你挑起来的 等着瞧吧
-头冲上   -尾巴冲上
我讨厌这个工作
-这是比赛？ 这是比赛！  -这不是比赛
这是战争
嘿 嘿 嘿 今天死亡坑天气不错
-这是胜者为王的比赛  -七局四胜
获胜者将得到整片巴西栗子林
这就像足球 这我会玩
有什么特别的战术吗？4-4-2 还是 5-4-1
怎么踢 教练 我踢什么位置
事实上我给你准备了一个合适的位置
水 这儿有水 来喝水吧
好的 谢谢
罗伯特 他所向披靡势不可挡 到处都是他的身影
-加油罗伯特  -哼 这我也能行
罗伯特和对手保持距离 他正在向前冲 向前冲
他射门了！
进啦！
哦 费利佩抢到了球 红金刚鹦鹉要扭转局面
费利佩传给提科 提科传给马里奥
马里奥传给凯撒 凯撒传给安东尼
安东尼射门得分！
嘿 去你的吧
费利佩 罗伯特 费利佩 罗伯特...
射门
-这一定很疼  -上 上
费利佩 利佩 利佩
-犯规   -嘿 得了吧 裁判
-好吧 你上  -真的？
没说你 你
学着点吧 送水小子
-好吧  你  你上吧  -好的
开始吧 教练
嘿 爸爸
现在尤为替补队员上场了 他会是秘密武器吗？
他不就是那个送水的吗
没人防我  没人防我 把球传给我啊
传给我 我这儿没人防守 快传给我啊
把球传给我
-谢谢你把球传给我  -借用一下
罗伯特向前挺进 他避开一个防守 又避开一个
罗伯特 进啦
目前的比分 3比3
接下来谁先进球 谁就赢得比赛
我来接 我来接
加油 布鲁
哇 送水小子突然表现出了专业水准
把球传给罗伯特
快传球  快传球！
-布鲁 等等  -我自己能搞定
看上去这个秘密武器 突然走火了
我们来看看艾迪现在的反应
我要杀了这只该死的宠物
哦 老艾迪
看样子你们没有坚果吃了 只能减肥了
这场比赛在我们那儿会传为佳话的
我真不该对人类的宠物报抱什么希望
嘿 刚才你怎么回事儿啊？
我太想融入这个大家庭了
但我可能永远都不能成为你爸爸希望的那样了
-你..说什么？   -我想我们该回家了
-我正要跟你说呢   -跟我说什么？
布鲁 看看周围
孩子们这里 在野外玩的这么的开心
也许这里就是我们的家
我们的家？ 这里是我们的家？
我尽全力适应这里 帮助他们 可我做什么都不对
这不是我们的家 珠儿
也许属于你 但不是我的
知道吗？ 你应该清楚你到底需要什么
而且
别老想着你自己 也为我们想想吧
出发 出发 快点
太好了
琳达 图里奥
再见 琳达
-再见 小腰包   -请在能拐弯的时候拐弯
抱歉 GPS小姐 不是你的错 是我的不对
再见 煎饼 再见 咖啡
再见 咖啡
琳达？
琳达
艾迪说的对  你是个叛徒
-等等 你不明白？  -我有什么不明白的 与人类为伍？
-你对人类了解多少？  -哦 我很了解他们
他们引诱你 把你抓起来
他们还给你洗脑！
鹦鹉要吃饼干吗 要吃饼干吗？
不 我受够饼干了 我讨厌饼干
-快走 罗伯特  -是他们 是他们 是他们！
让开
不要 不要 我不要饼干
你冷静点
听好 我们有个机会阻止这一切
我去找到我的朋友 你飞回去警告大家 明光吗？
-明白   -好的 快去！
人类 人类
-往你的左边 不右边 右边  -左还是右？
你的右腿 我的左腿
现在往上爬
爬  爬
差一点了 就快到了
琳达 我真的很抱歉
虽然情况很糟糕 但是我全世界哪儿也不想去 只想和你在一起
哪怕是被拴在一棵树上 （第一部里Jewel和blu）
哦 琳达
布鲁 布鲁
-琳达？   -下面！
-啊 布鲁  -你怎么在这儿？
这里很危险
真难以置信 里约飞到这儿有2000英里
-我们跟着他  -太神奇了
我就说我听到他的声音了
给我钥匙
一切都完了 人类 人类
那些光 那些光 不...
自从我们找到他 他就不停的说胡话
伐木工来了 布鲁和他们在一起
-他是个叛徒  -不 布鲁是想帮我们
什么？ 就他自己？  -我们快撤
离开这里 所有的鸟立刻出发
爸爸 这次不行 我不能和你一起走
你必须和我一起走 我不能再让家人面临危险
布鲁也是我的家人 我不会丢下他的
不用担心
你没事吧
听着 埃德沃德 也许我不是这里最有鸟样的鸟
就现在来说 这是好事
你了解丛林 我了解人类
我们合作就能阻止伐木工
不能让他们夺走我们的家园
虽然这里又热又吵 到处是恐怖的虫子
可这是属于我们的 我们要为他而战
-谁跟我去？  -我跟你...（有点阿凡达的感觉..）
还有谁吗？
停下 停下
停下！
哦 这就对了 请尊重热带雨林
我就知道  我就知道 我就...
你这事要去哪儿？那只不过是一群该死的鸽子
给我回去干活
你带头 布鲁
终于叫对了 你叫我布鲁
对 我叫布鲁！
哦 哦 对 有蓝色羽毛的鸟
团结在一起
准备好了吗？ 现在往下
往上
倒飞！
我会活下去 我会活下去
-抓到了   -哇 好准
我才不怕什么鸟呢
进攻
-亚马逊保卫战开始了  -准备 扔
击掌
-为什么？为什么？   -给我振作起来
炮弹来了
停下 他在那儿 查理 给我准备鼻射炮
-迪耶戈   -这才对嘛
准备 瞄准 开火
又失手了
-干得好 迪耶戈  -我们是最棒的团队
嘿 你以为我会错过这个机会？
比赛开始
嘿 快回来 一群饭桶 没用的东西
小心
要打架 找个个子和你一样大的
-不 不  -接住你了 接住你了
别害怕 没事了 你安全了
那就是琳达
还是这么默契 布鲁
真是的 什么事都得我亲自干
-给我滚开  -不 没有人可以抢我的戏
棒棒糖？
什么？
你在干嘛？ 快走 快逃命吧
-快放开  -我就不
你疯了吗？ 你会把我们两个都害死的
-飞呀 似曾相识吧 布鲁  -奈杰尔
-布鲁  -奈杰
你
你要为你的罪恶付出最惨痛的代价
住手 别过来
用我愤怒的羽毛 扇肿你的脸
-你没必要 没必要这么做  -我就是想这么做
哦天哪 查理 机会来了
稳住 稳住
扇耳光比赛
就是现在 发射！
奈杰尔
我就要死了吗？
我太年轻 又太英俊 天妒英才
-鲍勃  -等下 那不是鲍勃
我就说我见过他
这是我最后的谢幕
现在只剩下站票了
再见
不！！我干了些什么啊
如果不能与汝同生 那我不如死了算了
那只青蛙它没有毒
-什么？  -我们没有死？
这个品种经常被搞错
它是只假的箭毒蛙
从它粉色的斑点就能看出来
可我父母从小告诉我说 我有剧毒
叫我别碰任何人
你是你爹妈充话费送的吧？
那么现在 我们可以在一起啦
-奈杰尔 奈杰尔 我的维克多  -谁来救救我
-我绝对不会放你走的  -不 不 我会学好的
不 不 查理
查理
这是违反自然法则的
嘿 伙计们 嗨 头发没弄脏吧
我们从亚马逊的腹地
为你带来特大新闻
多亏了图里奥博士和他的团队
这里的整片区域都将会制定为
国家野生鸟类保护区
我们大家会一起确保这里的安全
对吗 布鲁？
好消息还不止这一个
我们在丛林深处找到这只凤头鹦鹉
他好像和一只树蛙黏在一起
我们会把它带回里约
进行持续的观察
哦 奈杰尔 我们要去里约度蜜月啦
大家一起来 拍手 拍手 摇尾巴
这是丛林里有史以来最强大的明星阵容
下面请看--野性亚马逊
嘿 嘿 别咬我 别咬我
我的鸟儿朋友们
翅膀挥舞起来
亚马逊
这是我们最爱的绿宝石
从密林来到你的面前
拍打的是心跳的节奏
演绎的是自由的音符
这是我们最爱的绿宝石
来自我们生活的地方
充满着自由和欢乐
时光不停飞逝
丛林就像一阵清风 一个奇迹
快穿上舞裙 随时有人叫你跳舞
你好 亚马逊
-嘿 路易兹   -嘿 小鸟们 我来了
欢迎来到丛林
罗汉龟
唱吧 宝贝儿
你确定要在亚马逊安家吗？
-这里有热又有恐怖的虫子  -开什么玩笑
我可是丛林先生 充满野性而且还很有鸟样
夏天还是去里约避暑吧
你是我的唯一 珠儿
奥...
结束了吗？
《Rio Rio (feat. B.o.B)》